Guide to the Kenneth M. Reardon papers, 1971-2015.
Reardon, Kenneth M. papers
- Series IV. Major Projects
  - University of Memphis
    - Vance and Green Machine
      - Vance
        - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Communications, November 2012 (Box 13, Folder 11)
        - Choice Neighborhood - Press, July 2011 (Box 13, Folder 12)
        - Vance Avenue Strategy, October 2012 - December 2012 (Box 13, Folder 29)
          Includes myths and facts about privatization, Vance Avenue Collaborative documents and organizing material such as a large map of actions.
        - Vance Avenue Press, October 2010 - February 2013 (Box 13, Folder 30)
        - Correspondence - Vance Shooting, June 19, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 31)
        - Vance Avenue Staff Meeting, September 2010, February 2012 - May 2012 (Box 13, Folder 32)
        - Vane Community Transformation Plan Presentation Materials, Undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
        - Vance Articles, November 30, 2007, Undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
        - Public Hearing, April 2014 (Box 13, Folder 35)
          Includes public hearing PowerPoint by City of Memphis Division of Housing and Community Development, sample housing choice voucher program application, and Vance Avenue Collaborative Spring Report "HUD Rejects MHA's Vance Avenue Choice Neighborhood Grant Proposal"
        - Vance Avenue Collaborative Housing Voucher Meeting, February 19, 2010, September 2013, April 2014 (Box 13, Folder 36)
          Includes "South of the Forum Peabody/Vance Planning Initiative", informative voucher packet
        - University of Memphis (UM): Foote Homes Campaign, March 2014, February 2015 (Box 13, Folder 37)
          Includes "Improve Don't Remove Foote Homes" campaign meeting materials, sign in sheets, posters, petitions and press
        - Vance Avenue Community Transformation Plan: Student Summaries, April 2015 (Box 13, Folder 38)
        - Student Evaluations and Best Practices - Hope VI, December 2011, Undated (Box 13, Folder 39)
        - Hope VI - Related Memphis and National Press, June 2009 (Box 13, Folder 40)
          Articles related to HOPE VI developments in the City of Memphis and nationwide, covering housing, historic preservation, bio/high-tech industry and "river city" development projects
        - Foote Homes Press, 2010 - 2012, Undated (Box 13, Folder 41)
          Includes press about Vance Avenue revitalization like "Out of the Ghetto", press release and more press.
        - Foote Homes, February 2012 - April 2013, Undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
          Includes "Foote Homes Residential Surveys" from Project Neighborhood Sub-Committee Vance Avenue Choice Neighborhood Initiatives, meeting notes, List of "Critical Issues" of "Foote Homes- Choice Neighborhood Initiative Application", Planner's Network Magazine.
        - Choice Neighborhood, 2011, Undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
          Includes "Vance Avenue Collaborative: Revitalizing a Historic African American Community. Exploring the Potential of a Family Entertainment District to Expand Minority Business and Employment Opportunities" (2011 Planners Network Community), Executive Summary of Excerpts from Memphis Housing Authority's Choice Neighborhood Submissions
        - Vance Avenue Contract Resolution, April 1994, June - July 2011 (Box 16, Folder 24)
        - Vance Avenue City Meetings, 2008, 2012 - 2013 (Box 16, Folder 25)
          Includes Choice Neighborhood Planning Grant, List of Deliverables to Memphis Housing Authority and Housing and Community Development
        - Vance Avenue G.A. Meetings, February 2012 - May 2013 (Box 17, Folder 26)
          Includes materials from meetings about the Green Machine and Vance Avenue Projects
        - Vance Avenue: Preliminary Planning, June 2010 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - "Current Conditions of the Neighborhood", "2012 Promise Neighborhoods At a Glance", map, and "Community Meeting Survey Analysis", 2011 - April 2012 (Box 17, Folder 2)
        - "Vance Avenue Collaborative Grocery Retail Potential" completed by Adrienne Johnson, December 11, 2012 (Box 17, Folder 3)
        - Vance Avenue Community Transformation Plan, 2013 (Box 17, Folder 4)
        - Vance Avenue Fact Sheet, Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
        - Green Machine: Education, Undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
        - Vance Campaign I & II, 2011 - 2013, Undated (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
          Includes Saving the Foote Homes and Vance Avenue Community Transformation Plan correspondence and materials from Historic Preservation, PowerPoints, papers such as "Struggling to Gain a Voice with HUD's Choice Neighborhood Program: A Post Card from the Shadows of the Lorraine Motel", applications, financial information, letter to elected officials, City Council Resolution, meeting materials, organizing and strategic planning, press, outreach material, stickers, flyers, Mid South Peace and Justice Center, permit and more.
        - Vance Campaign III & IV, 2012 - November 2013 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
          Includes Planning and Zoning Committee, notes, prayer service for Foote Homes, neighborhood petition, Vance Avenue Community Transformation Plan, press conference, National Register of Historic Places Information Packet, Vance Avenue Renaissance Plan Outline, and surveys.
      - Green Machine
        - Press, 2011 - 2014 (Box 13, Folder 13)
          Includes press for the MATA bus turned into a mobile market to serve the underserved communities such as "Feed the 'desert'"
        - Routes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
        - Updates, November 1, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 15)
        - Volunteers, Undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
        - Assisi Charitable Foundation, July 2012 - July 2013 (Box 13, Folder 17)
        - Design, January 30, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 18)
        - EBT, May 2013, Undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
        - Green Machine Fact, October 16, 2013, Undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
        - Forms, Undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
        - The Green Machine: Enhancing MATA's Community Service Record, Undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
        - General, June 2012 - April 2015 (Box 13, Folder 23)
          Includes routing information, meeting documents and notes, budget and proposed budgets, invoice and other financial documents correspondence from donors and foundations, requests, factsheet, list of MATA retirees, job descriptions, The Green Machine Mobile Food Market Year I & II Annual Reports, press such as "Memphis Mobile Market creates Food Oasis" in The Daily Helmsman, reports like "Bringing Healthy Foods to Underserved Urban Neighborhoods: Memphis' Healthy Foods Express", statistics of food distribution.
        - Healthy Memphis Common Table (HMTC), June 2012 - November 2013 (Box 13, Folder 24)
          Includes donors and disbursement, evaluation meeting documents, Orange Mound Parade Committee Documents, memo of understanding,
        - Invoices and Budget, January 2013 - August 2013 (Box 13, Folder 25)
        - Marketing, Summer 2013 (Box 13, Folder 26)
        - Meetings, October 2012 - December 2012, Summer 2013 (Box 13, Folder 27)
          Includes NBC Nightly News Pitch, Green Machine feedback forms, employee orientation, notes from meetings, PowerPoint "Vance Avenue Collaborative. December 2012 Meeting and Holiday Celebration"
        - Planning, October 2012 - July 2013 (Box 13, Folder 28)
          Includes physical transformation, meeting about bus stop input, notes from meetings, and planning documents
        - Mobile Fresh Food Bus Proposal, November 21, 2011 (Box 13, Folder 42)
        - Project Planning and Fundraising, December 2011 - January 2013 (Box 13, Folder 43)
          Includes a funding call list, "Second Annual Farm to Table Conference for Mid-South Producers" material, PowerPoints, work plans,
        - Opening, May 5, 2013, July 21, 2013 (Box 13, Folder 44)
          Includes program and festivities booklet with songs, drawings, and information, press release
        - Financial, June 2012 - July 2013 (Box 13, Folder 45)
        - Report and Feedback Forms, Undated (Box 13, Folder 46)
        - Vance Food Co-op, Undated (Box 13, Folder 47)
        - Press, August 2010 - April 2015, Undated (Box 13, Folder 48)
          Includes "The Social Activism Shift Since MLK's Assassination", "Memphis Mobile Market Creates Food Oasis", "A Fresh Start" and "Bringing Farm-Fresh Foods to an Urban Community Fighting Obesity"
        - Green Machine Fundraising I-III, 2011 - 2013 (Box 16, Folder 19-21)
          Includes press, meeting materials, fundraising material, reports such as "Bringing Healthy Foods to Underserved Urban Neighborhoods: Memphis' Green Machine", job applications, financial records, PowerPoints, correspondence, St. Patrick Community Outreach Inc., grant applications, Give365 Memphis' Grant Finalists, Whole Foods Market Supplier Application (St. Patrick Community Outreach Inc.), Tax information (W-9)
    - General Memphis
      - University of Memphis Fall Faculty Meeting, Undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
        A Brief Overview of the Vance Avenue Choice Neighborhood Team's Approach to Citizen Participation and Empowerment
      - Photographs, c. 2004-2007; CD-2474 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - 2020 Plan PowerPoint, c. 2006; CD-2475 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Executive Summery of The People's Plan, March 27, 2007; CD-2476 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Goldie - Ken Reardon, June 17, 2012; CD-2477 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Pro Tools, Undated; CD-2478 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Photographs, Undated; CD-2479-2480 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Mid-South Planning, October 2008 (Box 14, Folder 20)
        Includes material from Mid - South Planning 2007, University of Memphis Hosts National Community Development Leaders, budget and summit material
      - University of Memphis: Grants, 2010, Undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - University of Memphis: Green Cities Conference, April 30, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 22)
        Mid-South Planning and Zoning Institute Conference
      - University of Memphis: Rural Development Conference, February 2009 - April 2009 (Box 14, Folder 23)
        Includes "Strategic Planning for Community Economic Success - the Breakthrough Solutions Model" (2009 Mid - South Planning and Zoning Institute's Annual Spring Conference), Alicia Cobb's Resume, "Promoting Economic Development in Rural Areas and Small Towns during Tough Times. Lessons from the Field" Federal Reserve Bank Co-Host.
      - Mid South Planning, 2010 - 2011 (Box 14, Folder 24)
        Includes "Growing Greener: A Prosperous Shift with Sustainable Planning and Economic Development"; Growing Greener event documents (as well as revised documents) and materials, "Design as Dialogue: The Role of Museum of Contemporary Art Detroit in the Changing Urban Landscape", Tennessee Association of Flood Plain Management (TN AFPM), and correspondence about canceling the event.
      - Memphis Neighborhood Tour, September 11, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - Memphis Press, 2009 - 2012 (Box 14, Folder 26)
        Includes news articles and magazine articles such as "Ken Reardon Trailside Planning"
      - Youth in Action Regional Training - Growing up in Cities, January 2012 (Box 14, Folder 28)
        Includes "Hidden Heroes: Youth Activism Today" A video documentary and curriculum, PowerPoint "Organizing for Youth Empowerment"
      - University of Memphis Course Materials, 2008-2010 (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - Mattie's Greatest Ride, Undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
- Series V. Articles, Speeches, Lectures, Awards
  - Unpublished ESL (East St. Louis), 1993, Undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
    Includes unpublished work by Kenneth M. Reardon such as "Community Planning in East St. Louis, Illinois: A Participatory Action Research Approach", "Pursuing a Local Development Strategy Based on Import Substitution: The Case of the East St. Louis Farmers' Market", "Pursuing Economic Development Through Import Substitution: The Case of the East St. Louis Farmers' Market" and "History of East St. Louis Decline".
  - Published ESL (East St. Louis), Undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
    Includes published work by Kenneth M. Reardon. "The Evolution of Community Planning Practice in East St. Louis: From Participatory Action Research to Empowerment Planning" and "Neighborhood Planning in East St. Louis, Illinois: A Participatory Action Research Approach"
  - Published N.O. (New Orleans), September 30, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    Includes Transfer of Copyright document of "Overcoming the Challenges of Post- Disaster Planning in New Orleans.
  - Speaking Engagements - ESL PAR (East St. Louis Participatory Action Research), 1993 - 2000, 2007, Undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Speaking Engagements - N.O. (New Orleans), April 2008, April 2012 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Speaking Engagements: NY (New York), 2000-2004 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    Includes surveys, Parkside planning other neighborhood planning documents.
  - Speaking Engagements (Public Lectures), 1999 - 2015 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    Includes many speaking engagement speeches, brochures, agendas, conferences and notes from domestic and international engagements. Also includes reports, plans and studies.
  - Selected Speeches, 1986 - 2010, Undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Includes speeches from the Martin Luther King Jr. Social Justice Forum (2009), "What is to be Done When Good Ideas and Lofty Intentions are not Enough: Lessons from the East St. Louis Action Research Project, reactions to Obama's addresses, "Planning Education: Recommendations for the Next Phase of CRP's Curriculum"
  - PowerPoint Presentations, 1999 - 2007, Undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Includes "The People's Plan & Beyond"; Using Reflection to Promote Student Learning and Community Service Outcomes"; "Promoting Democratic Planning Arts: Techniques of Citizen Empowerment"; "South Memphis Revitalization Action Plan (SoMe RAP) Building a More Vibrant, Sustainable and Just Community", "Citizen Empowerment and Community Revitalization Through Participatory Neighborhood Planning"; "Planning Ethics and Professional Practice".
  - Kenneth Reardon Awards, 1981, 1987 - 2012 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Includes Awards for various projects and groups he's been involved with, awards from APA, AICP, Cornell, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign and more.
  - Confederate Flag, 2003 - 2005 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Includes Correspondence regarding a boycott of the Confederate Flag in South Carolina, Association of Collegiate Schools of Planning (2005 Annual Conference, Charleston, South Carolina), correspondence expressing Cornell's support of the boycott as well as the ACSP Board and the ACSP Conference.
  - KMF Biographical (Kenneth M. Reardon), May 26, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Includes booklet of Newly Tenured Faculty
  - Ken Reardon CARDI USDA Training, Undated; TR-10630 (Box 15)
  - New York Campus Compact Kick-Off, October 16, 2001; VHS V-8926 (Box 15)